Nico Del Rosario

Pasig

nicodelrosario0806@gmail.com

09178099144 | https://www.linkedin.com/in/nico-del-rosario-a84281211

Achievement Summary

Experienced Web Developer with 5 years of experience in the Startup Industry. Proficient in React.JS, Typescript, Robot Framework, and Browser Library. Successfully developed and deployed applications that increased client acquisition and improved system performance. Aspiring QA Automation Engineer with a focus on creating efficient and reliable automation workflows specializing in Robot Framework's Browser Library.

Languages

English, Tagalog

Work History

World Bank Group

QA Consultant • Quezon City

06/2024 - Present

Created Automation Workflows for Smoke and Regression Testing using Jenkins and Robot Framework.

- · Created automation workflows for smoke and regression testing using Jenkins and Robot Framework.
- Developed performance testing scripts using JMeter.
- Played a vital role in the manual and automated testing of the **Plansmart for Safe Schools Platform**, Resulting in a more organized development phase.

Philippine Institute of Volcanology and Seismology

Project Technical Specialist III - Automation Test Engineer • Quezon City

09/2023 - Present

- Integrated AGILE workflow for the R&D Division with the help of Gitlab, improving project efficiency.
- · Created automation workflows for smoke and regression testing using Jenkins and Robot Framework.
- Conducted performance testing using Jenkins and JMeter, enhancing application stability.
- Played a vital role in the manual and automated testing of the Platforms: **Plansmart for Safe Schools**, **El Nino Online Platform**, Resulting in a more organized development phase.
- Facilitated Design Thinking sessions for idea brainstorming with LGUs for **Plansmart for Safe Schools** and **Plansmart for Sustainable Human Settlements**.
- Maintained automated test cases for GeoAnalytics V2, Hazard Hunter, Maps Portal, and GeoRisk Platform.

Stack Educational Technologies

Frontend Developer • WFH

11/2022 - 09/2023

- Ensured continuous performance and stability of various applications through regular updates and bug fixes.
- Monitored system health, identifying potential issues early to prevent downtime.
- · Collaborated with development and QA teams to coordinate testing and deployment.
- Coordinated with the development and testing of new features, ensuring alignment with overall product goals.

Offshorly - Mobile First Websites | Enterprise Solutions | Digital Outsourcing

Intern Frontend Developer • WFH

09/2022 - 10/2022

- · Assisted in revamping the NFT app's home page, improving visual appeal and user engagement.
- Enhanced search functionality within the app, integrating filters for intuitive navigation.
- Contributed to code optimization, improving performance and maintainability.

• Collaborated on UI enhancements, ensuring consistency and responsive design across devices and browsers.

Freelance Project

Freelance Frontend Developer • WFH

09/2022 - 09/2022

Facility and Equipment Lending System

- Utilized React.js for App Development
- Created responsive frontend layouts, and components adhering to modern design concepts.
- · Technologies used: React.js, Typescript, React Query

Freelance Project

Freelance Frontend Developer • WFH

05/2022 - 08/2022

Attendance Monitoring System

- Utilized React.js for App Development
- Created responsive frontend layouts, and components adhering to modern design concepts.
- · Technologies used: React.js, Typescript, React Query

Freelance Project

Freelance Full Stack Developer • WFH

04/2022 - 08/2022

Gym Management System

- · Utilized Laravel Framework for App Development
- Created responsive frontend layouts adhering to modern design concepts.
- Technologies used: Laravel, Bootstrap, SQL, Heroku

Stack Educational Technologies

Frontend Developer • WFH

11/2019 - 11/2021

- I build web applications used for organization systems by incorporating various Javascript Frameworks.
- Worked in Agile-driven environment to effectively maintain project timelines and utilize available resources.
- Adhered to internal risk control and liability mitigation guidelines.
- · Completed full redesigns of existing websites to improve navigation, and enhanced visuals.

I have worked on the following apps during my stay:

- A Finance System for Stack Educational technologies as a Frontend Developer.
- A Learning Management System for Stack Educational Technologies as a Frontend Developer and a Product manager.
- An Admission System for Stack Educational Technologies as a Frontend Developer.

Xavier School San Juan

Full Stack Web Developer • San Juan

11/2019 - 08/2020

• Developed the OLSAT Monitoring System, which helped the Xavier School San Juan TRC office automate and increased their workflow rate up to 80%, finishing their supposed to be monthly tasks in mere minutes.

Xavier School San Juan

Full Stack Web Developer • San Juan

05/2019 - 04/2020

• Developed the Dynamic Queueing System, which doubled Xavier School San Juan's catering by organizing a systematic and organized flow for enrollees in 2019.

Xavier School San Juan

Book Staff • San Juan

02/2019 - 04/2019

Worked with books for inventory tasks

Hard Skills

- Programming Languages: JavaScript (Advanced), PHP (Intermediate), SQL (Intermediate), Basic knowledge in C#, C++, MongoDB, Python
- Frameworks and Libraries: React.js (Advanced), Typescript (Intermediate), Laravel (Intermediate), Basic knowledge in Express.js, Node.js
- Quality Assurance: Robot Framework (Advanced), Selenium Library (Intermediate), Browser Library (Advanced)
- Software: Adobe Photoshop (Advanced), Blackmagic Design DaVinci Resolve, Adobe XD, Markdown and Design, **Figma**
- Deployment Solutions: Git (Advanced), GitHub (Advanced), GitLab (Advanced), Jenkins (Intermediate), Basic Knowledge in Bitbucket and Heroku

Soft Skills

- · Attention to Detail
- · Problem-Solving
- · Analytical Thinking
- Communication
- Adaptability
- Time Management
- Collaboration
- · Critical Thinking
- Creativity
- Patience and Perseverance
- Proofreading
- Self Awareness
- Efficiency
- Entry Management
- · Work Life Balance

Education

Polytechnic University of the Philippines

Bachelor of Computer Science, Computer Engineering • Manila,

09/2023

College

- Participated in various workshops:
 - PHP
 - Linux & Ethical Hacking
 - Cryptocurrency
 - Information Security
 - UI/UX Design

STI College - Ortigas-Cainta

Mobile and Web Programming • Cainta,

03/2018

Senior High School

- · Graduated with Highest Honors
- Member of Developers of Next Advanced Technologies
- Recepient of BCE Scholarship
- Thesis: BAYANI (Available in Playstore)
- Gained Proficiency with Basic Programming Languages

Manggahan High School

ICT · Pasiq, 03/2016

Junior High School

- · Graduated with High Honors
- Gained Proficiency with Photoshop

Accomplishments

- Developed a game entitled "BAYANI" which won Best 2D game, Best Educational Game, Best Game overall at STI Ortigas-Cainta 2018 SHS Expo.
- Supervised a team of 4 staff members which delivered a working prototype of an app for one Startup company that resulted in securing a business deal with a client.
- Led multiple teams in doing successful freelance projects which helped the clients in their respective businesses.

Licenses & Certifications

- C++ sololearn
- PHP sololearn
- · SQL sololearn
- JavaScript sololearn
- React: Testing and Debugging LinkedIn
- React: Creating and Hosting a Full-Stack Site LinkedIn
- · Learning Docker LinkedIn
- Microservices Foundations LinkedIn

References

• Bob Mathew Sunga - 0020284596